（忆往昔）
抱歉 我总是忘
Oh, I'm sorry. I always forget.
我可以不让人们看到我 除非我想显现
People can't see me unless I want them to see me.
上帝
God!
就喊我恰克吧
Just call me Chuck.
我在找上帝
I'm looking for God.
你能看到吗
Do you see what's happening?
你的天选之民 他们在受苦
All your chosen, they are suffering!
现身吧
Show yourself!
叫我多纳泰罗就好
Call me Donatello.
这人是个先知吗
This guy's a prophet?
他并不知道自己排在凯文之后
He had no idea he was next in line after Kevin.
怎么能知道 他当时还没被上帝之力击中呢
How would he? He hadn't gotten hit by the God power yet.
阿玛拉呢 她是你妹妹
What about Amara? She's your sister.
我也为她承担了责任
I took responsibility for her, too.
把她锁了起来
Locked her away.
那你就要让阿玛拉赢吗
So you're just gonna let Amara win?
被你妹妹杀死怎么能叫策略
How is death by your sister a strategy?
我了解她
I know her.
她会毁灭你的
She's gonna eliminate you,
然后她会毁掉你创造的一切
and then she's gonna destroy everything that you've created.
这是她亲口跟我说的
She's told me this, personally.
你需要一切的帮助
You need all the help you can get.
我们计划把路西法从阿玛拉那儿救走
The plan is to rescue Lucifer from Amara.
然后让他把我们从阿玛拉的藏身处瞬移出来
Then he teleports us out of Amara's hideout.
然后我们说服恰克和他一起去打她
and we convince Chuck to use him to fight her.
我们要怎么拖住阿玛拉 然后去
And how are we supposed to keep Amara busy while we're…
解救路西法
liberating Lucifer?
你在想什么 有什么变了
Where are your thoughts? Something's different.
好了 梅塔特隆 快走
All right, Metatron, come on!
没事 萨姆 你走吧 我来应付她
It's okay, Sam. You go. I got this.
书记员
The secretary.
别毁了宇宙
Spare the universe.
省省吧
Spare this.
（如今）
你去哪了
So, where were you?
说来话长
That's a long story.
你感觉怎么样 我治好了你
How do you feel? I healed you.
嗯 我又没叫你那么做
Yeah, didn't ask you to.
儿子 别闹了
Son, be reasonable.
给我膝盖贴个宇宙创可贴
One cosmic Band-Aid on my knee,
怎么 你当我们这就算扯平了
and, what, you think that we're … we're even now?
我们该去院子里玩接球了吗
Is it time for us to go play catch in the yard?
去你的
Screw you.
伙计们
Guys?
你们怎么样了
How's it going in here?
听着 我知道我离开了好一阵
Listen, I know I've been gone for a while.
我错过了几百万个生日
I missed a few million birthdays.
是啊 你的猿猴一发出求救信号
Yeah, and then the second your apes send a distress flare.
老爸就回来了
Daddy's home.
不 不是那样的
No, that's not what happened.
这俩猿猴救了你一命呢
Hey, these apes saved your ass.
他伤不了你们
He can't hurt you.
你现在还控制我了啊
Oh, so you're controlling me now.
只是防护措施
No, it's just a safeguard.
伙计们 恰克
Hey, guys, uh, Chuck, um…
路西法 迪恩
Lucifer, Dean…
我们是不是该关注重要的问题了
think we can try and focus here, you know?
世界末日 共同敌人什么的
End of the world, common enemy, all that.
我敌人的敌人是我的朋友
The enemy of my enemy is my friend.
阿玛拉队加油
Team Amara. Go, Amara.
你不是真心的
You don't mean that.
你真不打算说
You're really not gonna say it.
他不打算说什么
He's not gonna say what?
去你的
Screw you.
去你们所有人的
Screw all of you.
孩子啊
Kids, huh?
[邪恶力量 第11季第22集]
路西法
Lucifer!
你早晚得
You know, at some point in time,
出来 跟…
you're gonna have to come out and … and talk to…
上帝说话
God.
简直是《青春满屋》最烂的一集了
This is like the worst episode of "Full House" ever.
如果老爸有话跟我说
If Dad has something to say to me,
叫他亲自来说吧
I'll hear it from him.
在此之前 我都会待在房间里
Until then, I'll be in my room.
才不是你的房间
It's not your room.
是我的房间
It's my room.
不管了
Whatever.
我们可以的 路西法窃取了王位
We can do this. Lucifer stole the throne.
他失踪越久 他的威信就越受削弱
His authority weakens the longer he's M.I.A.
政变的时机已到
The time is ripe for a coup.
所以 我把你们召集至此
That's why I brought you here.
我们可以携手夺回王位
Together, we can reclaim the throne.
我们可以携手重振地狱
Together, we can make Hell great again.
当然 我需要你们帮忙再招安别人
Of course, I'll need your help recruiting others.
等我们的人数占优势时 我们就出击
When the numbers are in our favor, we'll strike,
到时你们每个人
and each and every one of you.
都将赢得在我身边的一席之位
will have earned a place at my side.
就说他会这么做
Told you he'd do this.
「他」 做什么
"He"? Do what?
你总做的事
What you always do.
承诺恢复地狱往日的光辉
Promise a return to Hell's former glory …
却从不会兑现承诺
promises you never make good on.
回顾下你最近的统治吧
How about a rundown of your recent rule?
你先是罗威娜的走狗
First, you were Rowena's bitch.
然后是迪恩·温彻斯特的
Then Dean Winchester's.
然后是阿玛拉 路西法
Then Amara's, then Lucifer's.
几周前 你还在清扫地板
A few weeks ago, you were cleaning these floors…
而且是用舌头舔
with your tongue.
我们是可以夺回地狱 但何必呢
We could retake Hell, but why bother?
世界要完了 这次
The world's ending, and this time…
地狱也要一起完了
Hell's ending with it.
除非你有计划打败黑暗
Unless you've got a plan to defeat the Darkness.
那这就还是老样子
Well, then, this is just more of the same …
克劳力大王的蹩脚晚餐小剧场
King Crowley's bad dinner theater.
既然你是这么想的 何必来呢
If that's the way you feel, why did you show?
我们想看猴子跳舞
We wanted to see the monkey dance…
就这最后一次
one last time.
跟他谈谈
Talk to him.
没用的
Won't do any good.
为什么
Why not?
因为我不能把他想要的给他
'Cause I can't give him what he wants.
那是什么
And what's that?
每个人都想要的
What everyone wants …
我妹妹 我的孩子们 你们这些人类
my sister, my children, you humans …
都想要个道歉
an apology.
大大的「对不起」
A big, wet "I'm sorry."
那就跟他道歉啊
Well, so give it to him.
他又不是管你要武器
It's not like he's asking for a weapon.
或是地狱或天堂
or for Hell or for Heaven.
就是一句话嘛
He's asking for words.
如果我不觉得抱歉 就不能说
I can't say I'm sorry if I'm not.
他要我道歉的事
What he wants an apology for,
我是为了人类 为了世界才那么做的
I did it for humanity, for the world.
路西法想要的跟大家想要的一样 干掉阿玛拉
Look, Lucifer wants what everybody wants … Amara gone.
给他点时间冷静下来就好
Okay, let's just…give him a little time to cool off.
（世上最棒的老爸）
不知道你是否注意到了
Okay, well, I don't know if you noticed,
但我们现在偏偏就是没有时间了
but a little time is not something we have.
末日即将到来了
The end is freakin' nigh.
（路易斯安那州 大岛县）
罗威娜
Rowena.
门没锁
Door not locked.
玩灵魂出窍是闹什么鬼
What all that astral projection bull for?
我们关系又不太好 柯丽雅
We're hardly on the best terms, Clea.
闯进来之前 我想看看有没有巫术袋
Before barging in, I just wanted to check for hex bags.
或是
or a …
那个
That.
你想要什么
What you want?
我在研究一个咒语 需要一个帮手
I'm working on a spell. It requires a second.
帮手
A second?
你怎么不去找夏丽斯
Well, why don't you ask Charisse.
梅洛蒂 或托马辛
or Melodie or Thomasin?
是啊 你一时任性的时候
Oh, yeah, you torched them all.
把她们都烧了
in one of your impetuous little fits.
世界末日要来了 柯丽雅
The world's ending, Clea.
（死亡）
废话
Well, duh.
但你不该为世界末日烦恼啊 罗威
The end times shouldn't bother you, though, Row.
你是只老鼠
You a rat.
你在哪艘沉船上都能找到出路
Find your way off any sinking ship.
说得对
Damn right.
我在研究的咒语出自《诅咒之书》
The spell I'm working on is Book of the Damned magic,
可以让我们穿越回去
and it can get us back.
我们可以为自己争取几个世纪的生命
We can buy ourselves a few more centuries of life.
为我们逆转时间
Turn back the clock for us…
否则这世界就要不可避免地毁灭了
before the world inevitably goes bye-bye.
你怕了
You're scared.
是啊
Aye.
我跟黑暗面对面过
I came face-to-face with the Darkness.
我们当年听到过几次天启的钟声
The apocalypse bell's been rung a few times in our day,
但当我看着她时 我看到了
but when I looked inside her, I saw it.
不仅是世界 天堂和地狱的终结
Not just the end of the world, Heaven and Hell …
是魔法的终结
the end of magic.
古希腊
Greek antiquity…
否则免谈
or no deal.
中世纪
Middle Ages.
我知道 不是做女巫的好时代
I know, not the best time to be a witch.
或是黑人女子
Or a black woman.
难道古希腊就更好吗
And the Greek Age was better?
我喜欢经典 我能搞定
I'm a fan of the classics. I'll make it work.
成交
Deal.
你们其中一位得先开口
One of you is gonna have to, uh, go first.
这样吧 路西法
You know what? Uh, Lucifer, y-you, uh…
你说只要上帝到场 你就乐意坐下谈谈
you agreed to have a sit-down if … if God would show,
那么…
so…
恰克 你说过你会开口的
And, Chuck, you … you did say you'd talk.
他先说
Him first.
是我该得到一个解释
I'm the one who's owed an explanation.
好吧 我们试试用「我觉得」来开头
Okay, let's … let's try "I feel" statements.
菲尔医生（真人秀心理医生）
Dr. Phil.
嗯 好 当然了
Oh, yeah, of course. Obviously.
我很抱歉你觉得
I am sorry that you feel…
我背叛了你 我毫无道理
that I betrayed you, that I acted without cause.
很抱歉 你不明白是你让我别无选择
I'm sorry that you can't see you gave me no choice.
- 我说完了 - 你们听到了吧
- I'm good. - You heard that, right?
我们都知道你是上帝 但是
W-We all know that you are God, um, but…
你能不能别那么…老大
maybe could you be a-a little less…Lordly?
但我就是老大啊
But I am … I-I'm the Lord.
瞧他啊
There he goes.
我做了不得已的事
I did what I had to do.
为了创造世界 我必须把阿玛拉关起来
To create the world, I had to lock Amara away.
血印败坏了你后
And when the Mark corrupted you.
我发现你对人类构成威胁
and I saw that you posed a threat to humankind,
我把你也关了起来
I did the same with you.
不 你背叛了我
No, you betrayed me.
你为了关她而给了我血印
You gave me the Mark to lock her away,
结果后来它改变了我
and when it changed me,
那是血印不可避免的影响
when it did what the Mark inevitably does…
你就抛弃了我
you threw me away.
不 儿子 血印
No, Son. The Mark …
你一直对人类抱有敌意
You always cast a jaa diced glance at humans.
血印没有改变你
The Mark didn't change you.
只是放大了你的为人
It just made you more of what you already were.
我本来是你儿子
What I was was your son…
你的孩子
your child.
我凭什么把你置于其他人之上
Why should I put you first above all others?
你知道跟你当上帝的
Do you have any idea what it's like to argue.
老爸吵架是什么感觉吗
with your father when your father is God?
你说什么做什么都是真理
Everything is a tautology with you.
总是「因为我这么说的」
Everything is, "Because I told you so."
或者「那非做不可」
Everything is, "It had to be done."
当爹的都这样
Pretty sure that's all fathers.
那好
Okay.
好吧
Fine.
大局 作为上帝 你做了你必须做的
Big picture, as God, you did what you had to do.
那么微观来看呢
But little picture …
你是个糟糕透顶的老爸
you sucked at being a dad.
好吧 或许我并没把所有事都处理得很好
Okay, maybe I didn't handle everything perfectly.
但告诉我
But tell me…
如果我不赶走你 人类的安全有保证吗
could I have kept humankind safe with you on the board?
我知道你曾想顶替我
I know about your little bid to replace me with the angels.
那么 「新上帝」 你会怎么处置你
Okay, "New God, " what would you have done about you?
重点不在那儿
That is not the point!
真不敢相信我真要这么说 但是
I-I can't believe I'm actually about to say this, but, um…
路西法是对的
Lucifer is right.
他只想要一个道歉
A-All he wants is an apology,
你却只在乎对错
a-and you're too concerned about being right.
不肯跟他道歉
to … to give him one.
但道歉并不总是关于对错
But apologies aren't always about being right.
有时候只是需要道个歉
Sometimes they're just about apologizing.
是啊 道歉的一个妙处就是
Yeah, a-and the great thing about apologies is.
你不非得是真心的
you don't have to mean them.
我经常对萨姆撒谎 说我很抱歉
You know, I-I lie and tell Sam I'm sorry all the time.
对不起 瞧见没
I'm sorry. See?
这…
That's…
行了 场外观众就别掺和了
Okay, enough from the peanut gallery.
说啊
What?
换了你会怎么做
What would you have done?
无所谓
It doesn't matter.
你是我父亲 却抛弃了我
You were my father, and you forsook me.
是的
I did.
我本该平等地爱众生
I was supposed to love all creation equally.
本不该有偏爱的
I wasn't supposed to have favorites.
但你
But you…
你曾是我的最爱
You were mine.
我给你血印是因为我最爱你
I gave you the Mark because I loved you the most…
因为我以为你够坚强 可以承受
because I thought you were strong enough to bear it.
当我发现自己错了
And when I saw that I was wrong…
当我看着我的选择
when I watched my choice…
吞噬了
devour my…
我最珍爱的儿子
most cherished son…
我痛恨自己
I hated myself.
所以我惩罚了你
And so I punished you.
我很抱歉
And I am so sorry.
都没事了吧
So…are we good?
好 太好了
Okay. Great.
现在干什么
So what now?
抓住阿玛拉 把她关回去
We trap Amara, put her back in the box.
等等 什么
Wait, what?
嗯 你说得对
Yeah. Well, you were right.
是该摧毁她
She needs to be destroyed.
- 但我不能杀她 - 为什么
- But I won't kill her. - Why not?
阿玛拉被囚禁了数十亿年 但
Amara's been caged for billions of years, but…
但她一直在的
you know, she was always there.
她必须存在
She had to be there …
阴阳 黑暗光明什么的
you know, yin and yang, you know, uh, dark and light.
说明白点 恰克
English, Chuck.
宇宙有种和谐 平衡
There's a harmony, a balance in the universe.
光明需要黑暗 黑暗需要光明
Light needs dark, dark needs light.
如果把其中一个干掉了 那么
If you blow one of them up, then, I mean…
反正不是好事
It wouldn't be a good thing.
会是非常不好的事
It'd be really not a good thing.
终结现实世界那么不好
Like, end of reality, not good.
好吧 那么我们抓住阿玛拉
Okay, so we gift-wrap Amara.
把大家都集结起来
I mean, we got the team back together, so …
恐怕不行
Not quite.
原始阵容还少几个人
We're still a few members short of the original lineup.
第一次 我和兄弟们
Yeah, first time, it took the combined strength.
合力削弱了阿玛拉的力量 然后
of me and my brothers to weaken Amara before…
老爸才解决掉了她
Daddy-o finished her off.
即便是那样 也很惊险
Yeah, even then, it was close.
光是我们俩 不会成功的
No, with just the two of us, we'll lose.
好吧 那么如果我们想成功
Okay, so, what, we'll need more group therapy.
得继续给你和大天使做集体治疗吗
between you and the archangels if we want to have a shot?
米迦勒根本不能战斗
Well, Michael's in no condition to fight.
复活加百列和拉斐尔
And it's outside of my power.
也在我能力之外
to bring Gabriel and Raphael back.
你恢复了卡西迪奥
But you restored Castiel.
大天使不一样
Archangels are different.
他们是原始的创造
They're the stuff of primordial creation.
重建他们需要耗时 我们来不及的
Rebuilding them, it's … it's time we don't have.
好吧 那你需要什么才能获胜
All right. So what do you need to win?
你们有什么
What do you got?
我们能拿什么来替代大天使的神力
So what do we bring to the table to make up for archangel power?
我们可以试试再找些上帝之手
We could try and find more Hands of God.
多余了吧
A little redundant.
克劳力呢
Well, what about Crowley?
厉害的恶魔力量 前地狱之王
Big demon power, former king of Hell.
他当年也是个人物
He was a player in his day.
学我的啊 迪恩
Stealing my moves, Dean?
我猜猜
Let me guess.
你把路西法救回来了
You got Lucifer back in the fold.
他把你送了过来
He snapped you here.
不 不是路西法
No, it wasn't Lucifer.
该清醒了
It's time to sober up.
你闻起来像酒水店外的垃圾桶
You smell like a Dumpster outside the Liquor Barn.
这算什么 担心我吗
What's this? Concern for me?
多谢你企图重燃我们的兄弟基情
I appreciate your attempts at bro-mantic rekindling.
但我们都清楚 那条友谊小船已经翻了
But I think we both agree that ship has sailed.
不是为了这个
That's not what this is about.
我们需要你帮忙
We need your help.
我们有天使
We have the angels.
我还以为我把你们祸害得不轻呢
And here I thought I had made real inroads with you guys.
你错了 毒蛇
You thought wrong, Serpent.
- 毒蛇 - 我们讨厌你
- Serpent. - We loathe you.
我们永远不会喜欢你
We'll always loathe you.
好吧
Welp…
我是诚心诚意来求你们帮忙的
I came here to ask a good-faith favor of you folks,
但既然
but as you are…
你们这么杀气腾腾的
clearly less than kindly disposed,
或许你们愿听我的小蟋蟀一句
perhaps you'll, uh, lend an ear to my very own Jiminy Cricket.
你们好 兄弟们
Hello, brothers.
姐妹们
Sisters.
卡西迪奥
Castiel?
是我
It's me.
你以为你在我们眼中跟那个混蛋有什么区别吗
Do you think we see any daylight between you and the adversary?
罗威娜 她虽然狡猾 但她法力强大
Rowena. I mean, she's a snake, but she's a powerful witch.
而且她有《诅咒之书》
And she's got the Book of the Damned.
猫头鹰毛 蓍草根
We've got the owl feather and the yarrow root.
都齐了
Check and check.
猪下巴
A jaw of pig?
有了
Check.
你来干什么 巨人
What are you doing here, Giant?
拿来
Give it!
我们得先谈谈
Not till we've talked.
你走进了一个厉害的女巫团
You walked right into a powerful coven.
三个人才算一个团
Ah, it takes three for a coven.
女巫老巢
Witch's den…
还不带武器
without a weapon.
看我把你真变成一只鹿
I'll turn you into a moose … an actual moose.
你不能
You can't.
感受一下他的气场
Read his aura.
他有强大的保护
He under some potent protection.
从没见过这样的
Never seen that before.
听他说说吧
Hear the man out.
说啊
Well?
我们需要你
We need you.
让这些人加入
Getting these groups to enlist.
而且合作
and then work together,
不会是易事
it's not gonna be easy.
你不能直接控制他们吗
Couldn't you just compel them?
我发明自由意志是有原因的
I invented free will for a reason.
那我们要受原则的束缚吗
So we're tying our hands on principle?
不 强迫是不出好士兵的
No, you can't make an effective soldier by force.
他们必须自己愿意作战
They have to choose this fight.
但他们会想知道自己支持的是赢家队
But they're gonna want to know they're backing a winner.
那么
So…
我们得打上帝牌
We're gonna play the God card.
上帝回来了
God's back.
你之前就骗过我 萨穆埃尔
You've tricked me before, Samuel.
我凭什么要相信你
Why would I believe a word you say?
这倒是能解释他的保护气场
It would explain that aura of protection.
不是一般的魔法
Not no regular magic.
柯丽雅 亲爱的
Clea, dear,
等我们到了希腊克里特岛也要这样吗
is this how it's going to be with us in Crete?
就算上帝回来了 我管呢
Even if God's back, why would I care?
我可是异教徒
Hello, pagan here.
我侍奉魔法 不是上帝
I serve magic, not God.
抱歉
Sorry.
不感兴趣
Not interested.
我有兴趣
I am.
怎么 不能都侍奉吗
What? I can't serve both?
让我们听他说
Let's hear it from Him.
日后会的
In good time.
你们支持我吗
Do I have your support?
我都不忍看你 卡西迪奥
I can't even look at you, Castiel.
你用那个骗子玷污了自己
You befouled yourself with the Deceiver.
我屈从于路西法的每一秒钟
You know, every second that I've spent subordinating myself to Lucifer,
都是折磨
it's been a torment.
这在摧毁我 烧坏我的皮囊
It's destroying me, it's burning through my vessel.
但我毫不后悔
But I would do it all over again,
因为通过我 他和上帝
because through me, he and God,
他们将击败黑暗
they will defeat the Darkness.
这就是我在这场上帝的战斗中的角色
That's my role in this fight. It's God's fight.
你们也可以参与进来
You can play a part in that fight, too…
只要你们加入我
if you join me.
不行
No.
罗威 你带来的是逃跑计划
Row, you brought me a plan to escape.
而这是战斗获胜的机会
This here's an opportunity to fight and win.
她说得对
She's right.
没人跟你说话 大块头
Nobody's talking to you, big and tall.
我可以招来其他人
I can enlist others.
女巫姐妹
Sister witches.
你疯了
You're mad.
我们对付阿玛拉毫无胜算
We don't stand a chance against Amara!
罗威娜 亲爱的
Rowena, honey…
是有机会的
there is a chance.
（太阳）
权力的游戏 就像抢椅子
Game of thrones. It's musical chairs.
不过
Still…
我还是想要
I wanted it …
我想戴着王冠走向末日
to go out with the crown on my head!
这就是你向他们提出的
And that's what you offered them,
满足你自大的机会
a chance to stroke your ego?
你还奇怪他们为什么拒绝了吗
And you wonder why they said no.
我们有更好的提议
Well, we've got something better …
一个计划
a plan.
你可以袖手旁观
Now, you can sit on the sidelines.
看着世界完蛋
and watch the world die…
你也可以战斗
or you can fight.
你想重新夺回王位
You know, to be king again,
或许得先记起来怎么做士兵
maybe you need to remember how to be a soldier.
什么计划
What's the plan?
我们集结我们的部队
We assemble our band of brothers,
对阿玛拉发起全力攻击
hit Amara with everything we've got.
然后 趁她虚弱之时
Then when she's weak…
我了结她
I finish her off.
那么
So…
参照原本的战斗计划
a page from the original playbook.
但这次用的是女巫和天使 而不是大天使
This time with witches and demons subbing for archangels.
没错
Exactly.
我还是不喜欢
I still don't like it.
既然你可以杀她 何必关她
But why trap her ‭when you can kill her, you know?
你得承认
I-I mean, you got to admit,
如果直接动杀招 出错的概率会更小
there's a lot less room for error if you shoot to kill.
我解释过了
I explained why.
是啊 但何必留着她呢
Right, but why keep her in play?
好让她逃跑 然后我们再来一次吗
So she can escape and we can go through this all over again?
- 迪恩 你究竟想说什么 - 没什么
- Dean, what is this about? - I … Nothing.
难道只有我在理智思考吗
Am I the only one thinking rational here?
是因为她
It's about her.
萨姆 是因为他女朋友
Sam, it's about his girlfriend.
好吧 闭嘴
Okay. Shut up.
想想看啊
I mean, think about it.
迪恩·温彻斯特见到了宇宙第一怪
Dean Winchester meets the biggest evil in the universe,
居然不想动手
and he takes a pass?
拜托
Come on.
他想要爸爸做他下不去手的事
Now he wants Daddy to do what he couldn't.
他说的对吗
Is he right?
我才不要跟他吵呢
Oh, I'm not getting into it with him.
别想
Not gonna happen.
迪恩
Hey, Dean.
拜托 好的建议人人适用
Come on, what's good for the goose is good for the gander.
我们不就为你俩把话都谈开了吗
We opened a vein for you two.
我试过杀她
I tried to kill her.
但没成功
And it didn't work.
或许没成功是因为你不希望成功
Maybe it didn't work because you didn't want it to work.
或许你不想杀她
Maybe you didn't want to kill her.
你希望上帝杀了阿玛拉
You want God to kill Amara.
是因为你自己不希望阿玛拉死吗
because you don't want Amara to be killed?
是啊 或许我是有点不忍心伤害她
Yeah, maybe there's a part of me that just can't hurt her.
但如果她已经死了
But if she's already dead…
那就没得纠结了 是啊
Then she's already dead. Right.
好尴尬
Well, that got weird.
迪恩
Dean…
这些选择总会让我们紧张
…we always sweat this stuff, these choices.
但这次 上帝站在我们这边
But, for once, ‭we have God on our side.
这次 我们可以按他的办法走
I mean, for once, we can actually just do things his way.
那
That's…
那是个很简单的计划
That's a very simple plan.
简单
Simple…
但近乎疯狂
bordering on insane.
这是自杀
It's suicide.
没错
That's right.
还加入吗
Still in?
走吧
Let's go.
求你了
Please!
我什么都不知道
I don't know anything.
我才当了三天先知
I've only been a prophet for three days!
但你知道他在哪
But you know where he is.
我不会告诉你的
I won't tell you.
你不需要说出口
You won't have to.
堪萨斯
Kansas.
（世上最棒的老爸）
我不记仇
I don't hold grudges.
再说 那个狗脖套是挺聪明的
Besides, that dog collar was a lovely touch,
凸显了我的眼睛
really made my eyes pop.
今天我差点戴来了
Almost wore it here today.
很高兴你这么有幽默感
Oh, I'm glad you're such a good sport.
红发妞
Hey, Red.
还是那么美啊
Looking gorgeous as ever.
我觉得我是该道个歉
Hey, I think a little apology is in order.
你以为你是第一个企图杀我的人吗
You think you're the first man to try and kill me?
你好 费格斯
Hello, Fergus.
母亲
Mother.
孩子们好啊
Hello, my children.
就他
Him?
罗威娜 克劳力
Rowena. Crowley.
很高兴终于见到你们本人了
It's good to finally meet you in person.
我要为我这辈子做过的一切道歉
Sorry about, well, everything I've ever done in my life.
真的 你肯定不怎么喜欢我吧
Really, ‭y-you can't have been a fan.
是啊 我早就不怎么喜欢
Oh, yeah, I've been quietly rooting against you both.
你俩了
for some time now.
不过 我不能否认
Although, I can't deny.
你是我的一个罪恶快感
you're one of my guilty pleasures.
上帝啊
Oh, God.
行了 别调情 别吵架
All right, no flirting, and no fighting.
别做交易
Yeah, and no deals.
别说什么如果我们活下来
No talks about who is owed what.
谁欠谁什么的
if we survive this.
谁都不喜欢谁 这无所谓
Nobody likes each other. It doesn't matter.
我们只需要一起去打仗
We only have the fight ahead.
阿玛拉在找我
Amara's looking for me.
但我暂时做了针对她的防护
But I'm warded against her, for now.
我一旦放下防护 她就会出现
The second I drop the warding, she'll show.
她知道自己会面临硬仗 我们就跟她打
She'll be expecting a fight, and we'll give it to her.
震慑 震慑她
Shock and awe. Shock and awe.
你们的军队都准备好了吗
You have your troops in position?
罗威娜 说
Yes, Rowena?
计划真棒 上帝
Fabulous plan…God,
但是没有人觉得这个计划
but doesn't this strategy strike anyone.
不太讲策略吗
as a wee bit un-strategic?
我们不该至少试试偷袭她吗
Shouldn't we at least try to catch her off guard?
这个顺序是定好了的吗
Is that sequence set in stone?
恶魔 天使 女巫
Demon, angel, witch power?
在我看来第一梯队
Seems to me that the first response.
应该是最可牺牲的部队
should come from the most disposable force.
是啊 说得有理 小狗狗
Right! Good argument, Doggie.
那就让恶魔打头吧
Demons first, it is.
应该是最弱的当先
The weakest should go first.
所以是女巫
Naturally, that means the witches.
够了
Enough.
之后 是路西法
After that, it's Lucifer's turn.
身体攻击 一对一
Physical attack, one on one.
那小卡呢
What about Cass?
别担心
Oh, don't worry.
你宠物的安全是我的首要考虑
Your pet's safety is my highest concern.
相信我 他同意的
Trust me, he's on board.
等她被削弱后
Once she's been weakened,
我就把血印从阿玛拉那里夺回来
I will take the Mark back from Amara.
然后用来封印她
and use it to seal her away.
准备好了吗
You ready?
嗯
Yeah.
等等 什么
Wait, what?
上帝和我谈过了
God and I talked about this.
总得有人承担血印
Someone needs to bear the Mark.
那也该是我啊
Well, that should be me.
我都做过了 我已经坏掉了
I-I've had it before. I'm damaged goods.
是啊 你已经被玷污了
Exactly. You've already been tainted.
我不能把它转交给你 萨姆自动提出了
I can't transfer it to you. Sam volunteered.
先是小卡去做敢死队 现在又是你
First Cass is making kamikaze side plans and now you?
你就不能跟我谈谈吗
You couldn't have talked to me?
我们谈了
We did talk.
如果血印把你变成了疯子呢 那怎么办
And what happens when the Mark turns you psycho, then what?
你把我关起来 不让我伤害人
You…lock me up where I can't hurt anyone.
把钥匙丢掉
And you throw away the key.
萨姆 不行
Sam, no.
迪恩 你说过你无法打败阿玛拉
Dean, you told me you couldn't beat Amara,
所以只能是我
that it would have to be me.
所以我要上了
Well, this is it … me.
我就那么一说 天使能伤到她
I'm just saying, angels can hurt her.
以前就成功过
It's worked before.
如果你把让阿玛拉轻度呕吐叫「成功」的话
If you call giving Amara a mild case of the pukes working.
我们要伤害她的同时弄晕她
We're trying to disorientate her as much as hurt her.
你低估巫术 费格斯 一直如此
You underestimate witchcraft, Fergus, always have.
要说起来
If anything,
她这次大概都免疫了
she's inoculated.
全面恶魔攻击
Full-scale demon attack.
这才是我们的制胜因素
That's our "X" Factor.
我们谈过了
We talked about this.
该采取聪明的办法了
It's time to do the smart thing.
那我该做什么 坐在旁边看吗
So, what am I supposed to do, just sit by and watch?
不 我们都要打这场仗
No. We're both in this fight.
你要带领军队
You're leading this army.
照顾坏人吗
Oh, you mean babysitting the bad guys?
萨姆
Okay, Sam.
好吧
Okay.
上帝的计划
God's plan.
你好 阿玛拉
Hello, Amara.
你好 女巫
Hello, witch.
你怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
我以前进入过你的头脑
Been inside your head once before.
再找到一次不难
Easy enough to find my way back.
你还在找上帝吧
Take it ‭you're still looking for God?
我就跟他在一起呢
Well, I'm with him right now.
他就在这儿
He's here.
没错 就在里面
Yes. Right inside.
我们的交易呢
Our deal holds?
安全送我回过去
Safe passage back in time?
我可是替你冒了大险 背叛上帝啊
I went out on a limb for you … betrayed God, of all people.
你没有背叛上帝
You didn't betray God.
你背叛了我
You betrayed me.
你一召唤我 我就知道这是陷阱
I knew this was a trap the moment you called.
我不在乎
I didn't care.
我一直只想跟我哥哥单独面对面
All I've ever wanted is a one-on-one with my brother.
你给了我这个机会
And you've just given it to me.
问题是
The question is…
我要怎么报答你
how am I going to repay you?
[咒语]
好痒
That tickles.
你真觉得一个女巫的法力能伤到我吗
Do you really think the power of one witch can hurt me?
我不是一个人
I'm not just one witch.
[咒语]
够了
Enough.
努力值得称赞
Points for trying.
不
No!
别过来 不
Get back! No!
不不
No! No! No!
不
No!
你好 哥哥
Hello, brother.
你作弊
You cheated…
又这样
again.
但是
But …
儿子
Son.
对不起
I'm sorry.
为这事 为一切
For this, for everything.
终于道歉了
An apology at last.
道歉对我有什么用
What's sorry to me?
我在那笼子里憋了数百万年
I spent millions of years crammed into that cage…
一个人
alone…
害怕 企盼
and afraid, wishing …
祈求一死 就因为你
begging for death because of you!
我犯了什么罪呢 哥哥
And what was my crime, brother?
世界必须诞生
The world needed to be born!
但你不肯让我做
And you wouldn't let me!
阿玛拉 你让我别无选择
Amara, you give me no choice.
那是你的说法 我不这么看
That's your story. Not mine.
你驱逐我的真正原因
The real reason you banished me,
不许我存在的真正原因
why I couldn't be allowed to exist…
是你受不了
you couldn't stand it.
我们本来平起平坐
No, we were equals.
我们并不伟大或强大
We weren't great or powerful,
因为我们只有彼此
because we stood ‭only in relation to each other.
你以为你创造大天使是为了带来光明吗
You think you made the archangels to bring light?
不
No.
你创造他们是为了创造低等生物
You made them ‭to create lesser beings,
好凸显你的伟大
to make you large,
让你成为主
to make you Lord.
那是自负
It was ego!
你想做大人物
You wanted to be big!
没错
That's true.
但不全是如此
But it isn't the whole truth.
造物的价值和荣耀
There's a value, a glory in creation…
比我的骄傲或自负更伟大 更真实
that's greater and truer than my pride or my ego.
不管你称之为恩典还是存在
Call it grace, call it being!
那并不来自我
Whatever it is, ‭it didn't come from my hands.
它本就存在
It was there…
等待诞生
waiting to be born.
事实如此 就像我们的诞生
It just is, as you and I just were.
你被释放出来后 我知道你见识过
Since you've been freed, I know that you've seen it.
也感受到了
Felt it.
不非得这样啊
It didn't have to be like this.
我本是爱你的 哥哥
I loved you, brother.
好吧
Well…
你又赢了
you've won again.
做个了结吧
Finish it.
杀死我
Kill me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
不
No.
不 不
No! No!
真的对不起
I'm so sorry.
不 我不要再回去
No. Not again!
再也不要
Not ever again!
再见 侄子
Goodbye, nephew.
小卡
Cass!
我宁愿死
I'd die a million times.
或是杀了你
and murder you a million more.
也不要再回去
before going back there!
告诉我
Tell me…
既然你不肯改变
if you won't change,
我凭什么要改
why should I?
阿玛拉 不要
Amara, no!
抱歉 哥哥
Sorry, brother.
不
No.
阿玛拉 你做了什么
Amara, what have you done?
他死了
He's dead.
上帝死了
God's dead.
不
No.
他就要死了
He's dying.
我哥哥会逐渐暗淡
My brother will dim…
化为虚无
and fade away into nothing.
但他要先目睹接下来发生的事
But not until he sees what comes next.
他要先看着这世界
Not until he watches this world,
他创造的一切
everything he created,
和他所爱的一切化为尘土
everything he loves turn to ash.
迎接末日吧
Welcome to the end.